# **Juyong Jiang**

🛘 +86 18761157121 🗷 csjuyongjiang@gmail.com 🆀 juyongjiang.work 🖸 juyongjiang 🖪 Blog

## Highlight

My research interests are Computer Vision, NLP and GNN, with a focus on **Object Detection**, **Instance Segmentation**, **Attention Mechanism**, **GCN** and **Deep Learning**.

- Excellent Bachelor Thesis Award in Hohai University and recommended as the Outstanding Bachelor Thesis in Jiangsu Province in July. 2020.
- From Oct. 2019 till present, I am a **Research Intern** in **IVA**, **NLPR**, **CASIA**, working on instance segmentation in images & videos, supervised by Prof. **Jing Liu**.
- A paper "Cascaded Semantic and Positional Self-Attention Network for Document Classification" is submitted to EMNLP 2020, which is top-tier conference.
- So far, I have read more than 100 CVPR/ ICCV/ ECCV/ NIPS/ AAAI / ACL / EMNLP / NAACL papers so that I can understand and re-implement the new papers.
- More details about me are in My Homepage.

#### **Education**

Hohai University
 B.S in Computer Science and Technology
 GPA 88.76/100, 4.67/5.0, ranking top 8/107 in major

Nanjing, China

08/2016--07/2020

#### **Publications**

- Juyong Jiang, Jie Zhang and Kai Zhang. "Cascaded Semantic and Positional Self-Attention Network for Document Classification." In Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020. (Submit)
- Junfeng Chen, **Juyong Jiang**, et al. "A fault diagnosis system for rail transit platform doors based on deep learning." Chinese Patent. 201910613949.1.
- Jianjun Ni, Juyong Jiang, et al. "Bank card number positioning and recognition end-toend method based on CNN and RNN." Chinese Patent. 201910933476.3.
- Junfeng Chen, Juyong Jiang, et al. "Multi-regional precipitation prediction model construction method based on multi-graph convolution and memory network." Chinese Patent. 201911362437.9.

# **Projects**

- Video & Image Instance Segmentation Based on Deep Learning. (03/2020--Present)
  - Predict both the location and the semantic mask of each instance in an image & video.
  - Add the module of ASPP, CoordConv, DCN, Global Pooling, Self-Attention, etc. on base-line framework to solve some problems and improve performance.
  - ✓ IVA, NLPR, CASIA & HuaWei.
- Spatiotemporal Attention Probes Mechanism (09/2019--02/2020)

- Establish Spatiotemporal Graph.
- Use Query as a seed and then use the Markov Random Walk, Random Walk with Restart, Page Rank, etc. on Spatiotemporal Graph to form the interaction of neighborhood.
- Combine the node information in the neighborhood to generate polarity features.
- ✓ Temple University & Fudan University.
- Spatiotemporal Data Mining in Smart Cities Based on Deep Learning. (07/2019--08/2019)
  - Encode the non-Euclidean pair-wise correlations among regions into multiple graphs and then explicitly model these correlations using multi-graph convolution network.
  - Augments recurrent neural network with a contextual-aware gating mechanism to reweights different historical observations.
  - ✓ College of Computer Science and Technology, Zhejiang University.
- Bank Card Recognition System Based on Deep Learning. (03/2019--07/2019)
  - Data augmentation by using random cropping, rotation, various transformation, blur and noise.
  - Using CTPN & CRNN model to locate and recognize bank card number, respectively.
  - Developing a web page and an android app to display and use.
  - ✓ College of Internet of Things Engineering, Hohai University.

## **Experience**

 Image & Video Analysis Group (IVA), National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition (NLPR), Institute of Automation, Chinese Academic of Sciences (CASIA) Beijing, China

Research Intern 10/2019--Present

- Worked on **instance segmentation** in images & videos, supervised by Prof. **Jing Liu**.
- Department of Computer and Information Sciences, Temple
   University

  Philadelphia, US

Research Intern 08/2019--02/2020

- Worked on natural language processing, supervised by Prof. Kai Zhang.
- Pervasive Computing Lab (PCLab), College of Computer Science and Technology, Zhejiang University

Research Intern 07/2019--08/2019

- Worked on **spatiotemporal data mining** in smart cities based on deep learning, supervised by Prof. **Ling Chen**.
- Al Development Group, College of Internet of Things Nanjing, China Enginee-ring, Hohai University

Research Assistant 08/2018--07/2020

- Worked on **application development** based on deep learning, supervised by Prof. **Jianjun Ni**.

# **Awards and Honors**

- Bachelor Thesis is recommended as Outstanding Bachelor Thesis in Jiangsu Province
   (only 2 papers in Department of Information, Hohai University), 2020
- Excellent Bachelor Thesis Award in Hohai University (5%), 2020.
- Outstanding Student Honor in Hohai University, 2020.
- Outstanding Student Honor in Hohai University, 2019.
- Excellent Grades in Trash Classification Challenge Cup of Huawei Cloud Artificial Intelligence Contest, 2019.
- Top 10 Outstanding students, College of Internet of Things Engineering, Hohai University, 2018.
- Advanced Individual of Students at Social Practices in Summer Vacation. (Serve as Electronic Referee in The 19th Annual Games in Jiangsu Province), 2018.
- Research and Innovation Excellent Scholarship in Hohai University, 2020.
- Spirtiual Excellent Scholarship in Hohai University, 2020.
- Academic Excellent Scholarship in Hohai University, 2020.
- Spirtiual Excellent Scholarship in Hohai University, 2019.
- Academic Excellent Scholarship in Hohai University, 2019.
- National Encouragement Scholarship, 2018.
- Academic Excellent Scholarship in Hohai University, 2018.
- Academic Excellent Scholarship in Hohai University, 2017.

## **Mathematical Ability**

- 2nd Prize for Certificate Authority Cup Mathematical Modeling Online Challenge (Second Stage), 2020.
- 2nd Prize for Certificate Authority Cup Mathematical Modeling Online Challenge (First Stage), 2020.
- Honorable Mention for Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM), 2018.
- Honorable Mention for Certificate Authority Cup International Mathematical Contest in Modeling (CAMCM), 2017.
- Excellent academic grades in all mathematic curriculum. (Advanced Mathematics-A, Linear Algebra-A, Probability and Statistics-A, Mathematical Modeling-A, Numerical Analysis and Computing-A, Discrete Mathematics-A, Data Structure and Algorithms-A)

# **Programming Skills**

Language C / C++, Matlab, Java, Python

Web HTML / CSS, JavaScript, JSP, PHP

**OS** Linux

Framework Tensorflow, Pytorch